

PROFILE

Professional creative technologist with deep passion for helping people solve problems. He prides himself on being able to develop intuitive and consistent user experiences from conceptualisation to implementation.

With 7+ years of experience in studying and applying numerous design principles, critical thinking and user-centered models, he became very adept at developing digital interfaces that are able to scale and run on multiple modern platforms.

He has a keen interest in emerging technologies and relish taking on new opportunities that will allow him to further develop his skill set to reach new professional milestones.

EDUCATION

2008-2011

COMPUTING SCIENCE

Northumbria University

2007-2008

BUSINESS & ECONOMICS

EU Business School

SKILLS

- UX Strategy
- Design Thinking
- Prototyping
- Usability Evaluation
- Sketch
- Adobe Creative Suites
- HTML5/CSS3

GHIS BAKOUR

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER

Address: 02-22 Suites @ East Coast, 175 Upper East Coast Singapore 455277

Phone: +65 87 488 144

E-mail: fata.suir9@gmail.com//www.fatasuir9.com

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR UX DESIGNER

Titansoft Pte Ltd | Feb 2017 - Present

- Collaborate with product owners to ensure the product roadmap is truly aligned with the CX backlog to remain user-centric focused.
- Establish a scheme for new product capabilities in an agile work environment.
- Lead quantitative & qualitative user research studies to guide design decisions.

SENIOR UI/UX SPECIALIST

iCar Asia Limited | Sep 2015 - Jan 2017

- Lead and collaborate with UX professionals to build a design system for the entire list of acquired online businesses in the region.
- Introduce relevant CX processes and tools to help the organization stay focused and constantly innovating with new ideas.

HEAD OF DESIGN

Asia Venture Group | Jul 2013 - Aug 2015

- Develop product roadmap, lead design concepts and generate insights about an open review-driven platform to connect consumers with online businesses.
- Perform market research and manage stakeholders' interviews for an affiliate e-commerce platform to articulate vertical growth.
- Conduct usability and heuristics evaluation workshops for a grocery solution to increase conversions and customer retention rate.

FRONT END & WEB DESIGNER

Mindvalley Labs | Jan 2012 - May 2013

- Produce rapid prototypes and set the technical direction for the end product.
- Transform high-fidelity wireframes into functional web applications.
- Support the team to build an internal CMS with a solid front end architecture.
- Develop and ship quality online applications successfully in a team environment.

RECOMMENDATIONS

"When I decided to hire Ghis, I saw a very talented driven creative individual that wanted to make a massive difference in my organisation."

Pedro Sttau, CIO at iCar Asia Limited

"Ghis has rapidly transformed into a vital leader within the team and leaves a strong footprint in the company culture. I can recommend him without any reservation."

Philip Knuth, CEO at Knuth SA (Pty) Ltd